Defy your times
Woman Walks Ahead is a drama, history, western film directed by Susanna White.
Based on a true story, this riveting western follows a headstrong New York widow as she journeys west to meet
Sioux chief Sitting Bull, facing off with an army officer intent on war with Native Americans.
Catherine Weldon, played by Jessica Chastain.
Sitting Bull, played by Michael Greyeyes.
Silas Groves, played by Sam Rockwell.
James McLaughlin, played by Ciarán Hinds.
Chaska, played by Chaske Spencer.
General Crook, played by Bill Camp.
Woman Walks Ahead is a 2017 biographical drama Western film
directed by Susanna White and written by Steven Knight.
The film is the story of Catherine Weldon (Jessica Chastain), a portrait painter who travels from New
York City to the Dakotas in 1890 to paint a portrait of Sitting Bull (Michael Greyeyes).
Chaske Spencer and Sam Rockwell also star.
The film premiered at the Toronto International
Film Festival September 10, 2017.
It was released through DirecTV Cinema on May 31, 2018, before being
released in a limited release on June 29, 2018, by A24.
The film explores themes of native american, biography,
based on true story, sioux, north dakota.
The tone is emotional.